Daniel Davidson

in linkedin.com/in/danieldav k dadavidson.github.io

SUMMARY

Information technology and security professional with experience in system/network engineering, penetration testing, network security, endpoint security, vulnerability analysis, OSINT, project management, and strategic automation.

Highly adaptable individual who embraces teamwork, but also enjoys working independently. Carries a wealth of on-the-job experience and continual learning via Cisco Netacad, TryHackMe, Blue Team Labs, Vulnhub, LetsDefend, and home lab practice.

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Core Skills

- Value focused
- Team collaboration
- Strong communication
- Self-motivated
- Critical thinking

Network Engineering

- Cisco Switches & Routers
- Cisco Meraki SD-WAN/VPN
- Cisco Meraki Wireless
- DevOps Automation
- Palo Alto Firewalls

Systems Engineering

- Windows Server
- · Active Directory
- Powershell
- VMware Administration
- Linux Administration

Cybersecurity

- Penetration Testing
- Vulnerability Analysis
- Python
- Endpoint Security
- Micro-segmentation

2022 - present | Dothan, AL

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AAA Cooper Transportation

Network Engineer

Objective: Improve data center and site-based infrastructure.

- Support and manage day-to-day network operations of Meraki security appliances as well as Cisco switches, routers, and access points throughout 80+ Service Centers, Dedicated sites, and WFH sites.
- Design, implement and maintain converged networks and cabling infrastructure.
- Manage and maintain Illumio micro-segmentation for network security.
- Manage and maintain SolarWinds monitoring of networks and infrastructure.
- Work closely with vendors to support day-to-day operations including ordering, recommending technologies, improving network efficiency, and decreasing costs.

Dothan City Schools

Systems / Network Administrator

2019 - 2022 | Dothan, AL

Objective: Improve data center and site-based infrastructure.

- Managed and maintained switches, wireless access points, wireless controllers, and servers.
- Implemented secure and best practice design principles in company-wide system/network infrastructure.
- Provisioned identification and authentication for over 10,000 end users, devices, and services.
- Managed and maintained 100 UPS battery backups to aid disaster recovery plans providing better availability.

Jr. Systems Administrator

2017 - 2019 | Dothan, AL

Objective: Proactively ensure 90% uptime of network availability and consolidate critical infrastructure.

- Consolidated over 50 physical servers into 40 virtual hosts managed in VMware ESXi & vCenter with high availability.
- Automated driver, vulnerability patches, and software installation for 9,000 nodes.
- Monitored and resolved network infrastructure alerts to provide consistent availability of resources.

Information Technology Specialist

2016 – 2017 | Dothan, AL

Objective: Aim to provide better visibility of resources and automate workflows.

- Increased ticket resolution by 50% by scripting in-house tools to automate software deployment and device provisioning.
- Ensured proper installation of structured cabling, operating systems, and software.
- Resolved computer hardware, software, printing, email, and operating system issues.

EDUCATION

B.S. Cybersecurity and Information Assurance

Western Governors University

2021 - Present | Remote

A.S. Computer Information Science

Wallace Community College

2012 - 2015 | Dothan, AL

CERTIFICATIONS

CiscoSecurity Blue TeamCCNABlue Team Junior Analyst

Splunk Splunk Fundamentals **Axelos** *ITIL 4 Foundation*